# (757) 374 0095 · emilygmacon@gmail.com San Francisco, CA · www.EmilyMacon.com

# **EMILY MACON**

I am a visual designer who has brought brands to life, built front-end websites, and led teams across design and engineering. Visually, I'm an expert letterer, illustrator, bezier wrangler, and colorist. Cognitively, I'm a detail-oriented project manager, working fast without sacrificing quality, attention to detail, or losing sight of the broader goal. While I'm proud of my design eye, my most valuable quality is the ability to (successfully) implement any project from conception to completion.

I am currently an independent designer leading visual and product design for Eliqs, and contracting out several other projects for a wide array of clients ranging from new podcasts to NFL players. Prior, I led design for two years at a stealth sports robotics startup where I translated complex data and concepts into digestible visualizations across all user touches from company branding to the app, website, and beyond. I also recently graduated from Cooper Union's intensive one-year program where I honed in my craft of lettering & created two complete typefaces. Outside of work, I'm an artist primarily working with oil paints on a large scale.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **EMI ART & DESIGN LLC**

**Contract Visual Designer** ♦ San Francisco ♦ Feb 2016 - Present Projects ranging from lettering & illustration to web & product design

- Lead designer for Eliqs (contract) responsible for logo design & branding, illustrations, >40 custom can designs, all marketing collateral, and communications with both client and supply side partners
- Logos and branding for several clients including Falling in Love with Leah Lamarr podcast, Peyton Barber, Noh Leftovers, Vitabox, and other Bay Area startups
- Web design and implementation for Humboldt Legends
- Email templates, product site pages, and pitch deck for Feastly

#### **ICUEMOTION**

**Lead Visual Designer** ♦ San Francisco ♦ May 2016 – Dec 2018 Lead Designer under top robotics engineer Bérénice Mettler, Ph.D.

- Developed CueMate's visual language, including custom illustrations, animations, and brand guidelines
- Designed + coded website for CueMate products and iCueMotion R&D Lab
- Designed app UX/UI for iPhone, iPad, and Apple Watch; managed team of engineers for implementation
- Managed beta cohort validating technology and testing UX/UI

#### **MARKETBRIDGE**

**Designer**, **Consultant** ♦ San Francisco, Washington DC ♦ July 2013 – Nov 2015 I started at the boutique consulting firm as a Consultant. After clear interest in design, I was promoted to a custom Design role focusing on data visualization.

- Designed training tools for Saks Fifth Avenue associates to pitch SaksFirst credit cards to customers, doubling credit card activation within the first year
- Designed all infographics for Humana marketing campaign that contributed to 3x active user base; managed Humana's 3-person web development team, 13 copy writers, and 4 partners and redesigned the site UX, increasing both article page views and time on page by 20%
- Developed Microsoft's successful lead scoring model based on firmographic & behavioral data
- Designed >100 client-facing decks and misc. projects for clients such as PayPal, Cisco, Neiman Marcus, HP, and Dell

#### SKILLS AND TOOLS

- Adobe Illustrator for icons and general vector graphic design
- Adobe Photoshop for image editing and simple animation
- Adobe InDesign for books and zines
- Adobe Animate for complex animation
- Sketch for web and app design
- Invision for rapid prototyping
- Procreate for illustration & lettering sketches
- Robofont for typeface development and instances benefiting from more control over Bezier curves. For meticulous type design: Superpolator and MetricsMachine
- Extremely proficient in HTML/CSS and can navigate JS + React; track changes with Git

## **EDUCATION**

# UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA McIntire School of Commerce, College of Arts & Sciences

Double Major: BS Commerce, BA Studio Art GPA: 3.92/4.0, Dean's List all semesters, Graduated with High Distinction

# TYPE@COOPER WEST EXTENDED PROGRAM (COOPER UNION) Type Certification, 2017-18

Created two character complete type families Comprehensive study of type design technique, technology, expression, history & theory

#### **HOBBIES**

- Hand and vector lettering
- · Identifying typefaces in the wild
- Illustration and figure drawing
- Large-scale oil portrait commissions
- Creating custom jewelry
- · Making and eating sushi

#### **AWARDS & RECOGNITION**

Provided visuals & test question bank for How Business Works textbook now used in most US colleges ♦ Vance and Betty Lee Stickell Award, chosen as 1 of 15 students recognized nationally based on professors' recommendations and leadership qualities ♦ National Association of Newspaper Editors 1st in Best Illustration, 2nd in Best Political Cartoon ♦ Selected for city grant to have art on building exterior in ORF Arts District